Hi. In the dumpster room again,
recycling. What have we got? Uh
yeah. Uh that's uh not the greatest
find, but uh what is this? We have a
Oh, it's a TCL. Um nothing to write home
to your mom about, but it looks big and
it looks thin and it's got a power cord.
Um there's a couple of um empty bins
here. Uh the um chairs aren't breeding
that well at the moment. I'm just
tossing out my rubbish here. Yes, I've
only got like a little bin. This is my
bin from the uh lab. Tiny bin. But look
what we got here. This is a
giant looks like a giant like display
like industrial
display screen. And that looks like like
that looks like a PC in there, right?
And there's a Bosch um lithium power
Bosch something. What does it do? I
don't
It's a vacuum cleaner. There you go. A
Bosch vacuum cleaner. Um does it work?
Can I turn it on?
Yeah. Look, it works. It works.
uh battery. Okay, it's a bit bit
deadish, but kind of works. I think I'll
take that. Um check it out. You never
know. But look, there are um two more of
these giant TV things. Um like display
screens aren't cracked by the looks of
it. Oh, yeah. Yeah. Look, you can really
see. You can really see they're cracked.
I assume they maybe they did that when
they chucked them in. Um, doesn't seem
to be anything else here, but um, I'm
going to get that out. Looks bloody
heavy. Um, and that's a that's a PC in
there. Doesn't look like a great PC, but
it's a PC drive in it. So, I don't know.
Maybe this was looks like, you know, one
of those big industrial uh, displays for
like a, you know, a cafe or something
like that for displaying prices or
whatnot. But I'll get back to you.
Actually, this uh looks and feels like a
twoperson job actually. Uh like to get
this thing out. And I probably need some
like gloves or something cuz some of
this metal is uh is pretty sharp. So
like why they didn't leave them in the
recycle area, I've got no idea. But uh
yeah, they've just dumped them. LIKE
I'VE GOT TO GET ALL THE BAGS OUT and
everything to even have a snowballs
chance of getting this out. Damn. Well,
it turns out uh the metal bends real
easy, actually. And down inside there's
the uh display driver, but there's the
PC. So, yeah, it's obviously running
some sort of like, you know, um
animation type thing, like a you know, a
price list, a menu or whatever. And
there's a solidstate drive in there. So,
anyway, um that's a little small form
factor PC. Cute. Um, but the uh the rest
of it, um, not worth getting. Nice
little uh nice little power supply
there, though. Look at that jobby. Um,
I'll see what I can salvage. Well,
managed to get the power supply and the
mini PC and the solid state drive out.
And uh, there's the big ass power
supply. So, that other power supply was
just for the uh, PC. And uh, yeah, this
looks like it uh, draws a real thumping
amount of power. I mean, it's a massive
screen. What is it? 70 in or something.
Um, and there's three of them. So,
unfortunately, these ones are upside
down, so I can't get the extra uh
processor out of that one. But I'm sure
they're identical. But yeah, these
things are bloody huge and heavy.
Unbelievable.
All right, so what is this like 65 70
in? Haven't had a look yet. Let's turn
the power on. Have a convenient power
point down here. Nice of them to provide
the lead. Uh, no. I'm going to have to
find the power button. And it's on the
bottom here. That lights up. That's a
good sign.
Uh,
hello.
No. What do I do? Hold it down. What's
the deal? Or do something. Maybe it's
busted. I thought there'd be a good
chance this is uh this is working, but
nope. There you go. The light came on
again.
Got a big light bar, but
the actual image or no, not seeing any
cracks in it.
And if I press and hold, maybe
I expect to see a backlight come on and
a menu. But
w
further testing required.
Oh, these 65 in jobies just fit in the
lift.
Let's take it to the dungeon, shall we?
And here's the embedded PC board for it.
Very nice. It's quite old. It's was
actually end of life in uh 2019, but
it's from a company called IEI, which
are one of the big industrial PC makers.
And oh, where is it? Um, it's the Nano
HM 650. I'll whack up the data sheet
here and it's a very nice fullyfeatured
Intel um embedded PC. We've got a PCO
PCI 104 uh slot here. I've done videos
on PCI 104 before. It's got like RS 232
RS485
interface. It's got some, you know, IO
and other stuff. It's got an LVDS
interface which they used here to
actually uh connect to the panel. It's
got the dual Ethernets. It's got USBs.
It's even got integrated HDMI and VGA
and a whole bunch of other stuff. And on
the bottom side, we got some uh DDR4
memory. I think it comes with 4 gig as
standard. It's a really Look, look at
the silk screen on this thing. They
marked everything on this. It's just
unbelievable. So, yeah, it's a wonder
they had room for the bloody model
number. Um, yeah, it's a crazy dense
industrial PC board. And if you're not
familiar with industrial PC boards like
this, there's actually an embedded
standard. It's called Epic. And this is
what the form factor is. A couple of the
manufacturers back in the day came up
with the Epic form factor standard. And
uh so this is not your usual ones that
you'd find in like a PC case, but this
Epic uh form factor is u like industry
standard in the embedded uh PC world. So
yeah, very cool bit of kit, even if it's
old. So, well, let's power it up. See if
we can get it working. And yes, I was
right. It is a rotating display sign.
There were three of them. I know the
company that it came from. Um, this is
just a Windows uh desktop with like a
slideshowy type uh program on it. And
presumably they can update it, you know,
via the Ethernet. Oh, no. The Ethernet
wasn't accessible. Yeah. Not sure how
they up. It doesn't have Wi-Fi, so I'm
not sure how they update. I don't know.
Maybe there was an SD card on the side
or something like that which was
connected. There were various cables
buggering off, but yeah, I won't tell
you who it is, but uh yes, it was used
as an a window info uh display at a
company here in the corporate business
park. Um yeah, wipe your hard drives
before you toss them out. Just saying.
So, time for the old death lead. Uh
always keep one of these lying around
and I'll just uh stick some bare 240
volt wires up the clacker. No worries.
All right, let's plug it in. See if she
turns on.
And yep, powers up. No worries. I'll get
a monitor and keyboard and moose and see
what we've got. But I pretty much know
what it is. It's a second gen Intel uh
i7 jobby. All right. Well, I'm getting
nothing out of the HDMI output. So,
that's interesting. I'll uh try the old
school. Winner winner chicken dinner. I
don't think you can see that. Um, but
I'm in the bias menu, but it's cut it
like it hasn't sized it correctly and
it's super duper dim. So, I thought this
was a working monitor and I've turned
the brightness up and it seems like it
doesn't fix it. So, I'm not sure what
the deal is there. Yeah, that's that's
weird. I don't know. I might try another
monitor, but I've reset all these
settings on that monitor and it ain't
the monitor. It's um it's just fine.
It's like the output from the VGA is
just incredibly low. Maybe it's like
setup for the um LCD, the LVDS LCD it
was attached to and the VGA output is
just really dim for some reason. It's
rather odd. Aha, this Samsung jobby um
it just auto it was off screen but it
just auto adjusted but once again quite
dim. Yeah, not much. We've only got 2
gig of DDR3 memory, Intel Core i5. Um,
that's it. Just Core i5. I believe it's
a Yeah, second gen jobby. So, it's got a
G2 socket on there. And, well, Bob's
your uncle. Um, I don't know. Might be
useful for something one day. I'm not
going to go digging around trying to get
those massive um screens out of there in
the actual dumpster itself just so I can
salvage two more of these. Ain't worth
it. But anyway, that was an interesting
little score from the dumpster today.
This actually works a treat
the cleaning lady.
[music]
>> Actually, this thing is like a bought
one really. Um, I don't know if it's any
good or not, like as in the brand and
model, but up to 60 minutes battery
life. The Athlet Bosch Athlet 25.5 volt
lithium power.
Oh yeah. Says 25.2 volts, but if you
take the bag out, it actually says 30
volts, 500 milliamps. So I found a
suitable uh adapter for it. And we are
charging at constant current of 500
milliamps. And it's uh 28.98
compliance voltage and rising. So that
is good. It is accepting a charge. I
think we have a winner winner chicken
dinner here. It's a fantastic vacuum
cleaner for the lab. What a score. I
assume it's going to hold its charge. If
it doesn't, uh, can you get a
replacement battery for it? Probably.
Well, that's interesting. Look at that.
You can uh take the handle off there.
It's still charging. So, the battery is
not in there. Um, it looks like it's
just a uh control like that. You can see
just little PCB down in there with uh
four big contacts like that. So yeah,
the batter is uh built down into the
case somewhere, but at least it's
accepting the charge now. I'll see how
long it lasts.